<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<quran>

<sura index="1" name="Al-Fatiha" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
        Surah Al-Fatiha (The Opening) is the first chapter of the Quran, revealed in Mecca. It is considered the fundamental prayer of Islam, recited in every unit of daily prayer (Salah). Al-Fatiha expresses praise and supplication to Allah, the Most Merciful, the Most Compassionate, and seeks guidance on the "straight path." It is both a plea for divine guidance and an act of devotion, encapsulating the principles of faith and the acknowledgment of Allah's sovereignty.
        </introduction>
        <title>Praise and Glory to Allah</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Attributes of Allah</title>
                <description>The surah begins with praises addressed to Allah, the Lord of the worlds. It describes Allah as Merciful and Compassionate, highlighting His ability to guide and provide blessings.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Request for Guidance</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Straight Path</title>
                <description>The believers ask Allah to guide them on the "straight path," which is the path of truth, justice, and righteousness. This expresses the desire to live according to divine principles and follow the way leading to spiritual and moral success.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Call for Divine Assistance</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Seeking Allah's Help</title>
                <description>The verses include a request for Allah's help in daily life and a plea to avoid the path of those who have incurred His wrath or gone astray.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Unity and Communion</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Prayer in Congregation</title>
                <description>Al-Fatiha is a collective prayer recited in each daily Salah, emphasizing its importance in the spiritual life of Muslims and their communion with Allah.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Importance in Worship</title>
                <description>Al-Fatiha is essential in the daily prayers of Muslims, and its recitation is considered an act of devotion and a request for divine help.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Universal Aspect</title>
                <description>The surah is often seen as a synthesis of the spiritual and moral goals of Islam, expressing universal principles of faith, guidance, and gratitude.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Recitation in the Quran</title>
                <description>Its recitation is also performed on various occasions and religious ceremonies, reinforcing its central role in the spiritual life of Muslims.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="2" name="Al-Baqarah" city="Madinah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction> 
            Surah Al-Baqarah (The Cow) is the second chapter of the Quran, revealed in Medina. It is the longest surah of the Quran and covers a wide range of topics, including the fundamental beliefs of Islam, legal rules, and ethical principles. It discusses the stories of prophets, guidelines on prayer, fasting, charity, and family and commercial laws. Al-Baqarah also emphasizes the importance of divine guidance and patience, offering practical advice for living a life in accordance with Islamic teachings.
        </introduction>
        <title>The Foundations of Faith</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Faith in Allah and His Messengers</title>
                <description>The surah begins by affirming faith in Allah, His messengers, and the Day of Judgment. It describes the characteristics of believers, disbelievers, and hypocrites.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Role of the Quran</title>
                <description>It emphasizes that the Quran is a guide for the pious, offering direction for living a life in accordance with divine principles.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>The History of the Prophets</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Adam</title>
                <description>The surah narrates the story of Adam and Eve, their creation, their trial in Paradise, and their descent to Earth.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Example of Israel</title>
                <description>It presents the history of the Children of Israel, their blessings, and the trials they encountered, including their relationship with prophets like Moses.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Laws and Regulations</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Social and Legal Regulations</title>
                <description>The surah contains guidelines on various aspects of social, economic, and legal life, including rules on commercial transactions, inheritance, marriage, and interpersonal relations.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Laws of Charity</title>
                <description>It addresses obligations towards the poor and needy and the importance of charity and social assistance.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>The Importance of Community</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Collective Responsibility</title>
                <description>The surah highlights the importance of the Muslim community, solidarity, and collective commitment to Islamic values.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Spiritual and Ethical Commitments</title>
                <description>It emphasizes the practice of spiritual commitments, the purification of intentions, and individual responsibility in adhering to divine laws.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Worship and Spirituality</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Prayers and Pilgrimages</title>
                <description>The surah mentions aspects of worship, including prayers (Salah) and pilgrimage (Hajj), emphasizing their importance in the spiritual life of Muslims.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Religious Obligations</title>
                <description>It describes the religious obligations and expected behaviors of Muslims, reinforcing the connection between faith and daily practice.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Introduction and Description of Believers</title>
                <description>Verses 1-20: Presents the characteristics of believers, disbelievers, and hypocrites, and the initial teachings on faith.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of the Prophets and Ancient Communities</title>
                <description>Verses 21-141: Narratives of the stories of prophets, the Children of Israel, and the trials faced by these communities.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Legislation and Social Rules</title>
                <description>Verses 142-252: Rules on commercial transactions, inheritance, marriage, and other legal and social aspects.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Spiritual Guidance and Religious Practices</title>
                <description>Verses 253-286: Instructions on prayer, pilgrimage, charity, and other aspects of religious practice, as well as encouragement to follow divine principles.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Establishment of Laws</title>
                <description>The surah sets important foundations for Islamic legislation, influencing jurisprudence and social practice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Historical Reference</title>
                <description>It uses historical narratives to illustrate spiritual and moral lessons.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Spiritual Importance</title>
                <description>Al-Baqarah reinforces the principles of faith, religious obligations, and the importance of community in Islam.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="3" name="Al Imran" city="Madinah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
        Surah Al-Imran (The Family of Imran) is the third chapter of the Quran, revealed in Medina. It deals with the family of the prophet Imran, including Mary (Mariam) and her son Jesus (Isa). The chapter emphasizes themes such as faith in Allah, perseverance in trials, and the importance of following divine guidance. It also addresses interactions with the People of the Book (Jews and Christians) and highlights the importance of unity and justice. Al-Imran reminds believers to remember Allah's blessings and remain faithful to His commandments.
        </introduction>
        <title>The Importance of Faith and Devotion</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Declaration of Faith</title>
                <description>The surah begins by affirming faith in Allah, His guidance, and the truth of the Quran. It emphasizes the importance of pure and sincere faith in Allah.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Relationship with Allah</title>
                <description>It calls on believers to strengthen their relationship with Allah through sincerity, patience, and devotion.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Stories of Prophets and Righteous Families</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Family of Imran</title>
                <description>The surah narrates the story of the family of Imran, particularly the mother of Mary (Mariam), and the miraculous birth of Mary and her son Jesus (Isa). It highlights the faith and piety of this family.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Story of Jesus (Isa)</title>
                <description>It describes the birth, miracles, and message of Jesus, as well as the importance of believing in him as a prophet and messenger of Allah.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Relations with Jewish and Christian Communities</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Dialogue with the People of the Book</title>
                <description>The surah addresses relations with Jews and Christians, highlighting points of convergence and divergence between Islam, Judaism, and Christianity.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Call for Unity in Faith</title>
                <description>It calls for cooperation and respectful dialogue among different religious communities while affirming doctrinal differences.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Guidelines on Conduct and Behavior</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Ethics and Morality</title>
                <description>The surah provides guidelines on morality, justice, and integrity, emphasizing the ethical behavior expected of believers.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Importance of Patience and Perseverance</title>
                <description>It encourages believers to exhibit patience and perseverance in the face of trials and challenges.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Role of the Muslim Community</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Solidarity and Unity</title>
                <description>The surah emphasizes the importance of solidarity within the Muslim community and working together to achieve common goals.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Call to Spiritual Commitment</title>
                <description>It encourages believers to be spiritually committed and to follow divine teachings in their daily lives.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Introduction and Praise of Allah</title>
                <description>Verses 1-32: Introduction to faith in Allah, praise for His greatness, and the introduction of the stories of the prophets and the family of Imran.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Mary and Jesus</title>
                <description>Verses 33-64: Details about the family of Mary, the miraculous birth of Jesus, and the miracles associated with his life.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Dialogue with the People of the Book</title>
                <description>Verses 65-120: Discussion of relations with Jews and Christians, and the doctrinal differences between Islam and other religions.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Guidance and Practical Advice</title>
                <description>Verses 121-200: Guidance on morality, patience, solidarity, and the behavior of believers in their daily lives.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Focus on the Prophets</title>
                <description>The surah provides detailed accounts of the lives of prophets and important figures, highlighting the moral and spiritual lessons from their stories.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Interfaith Dialogue</title>
                <description>It highlights the importance of respectful dialogue and mutual understanding between different religious traditions.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical Guidance</title>
                <description>The surah emphasizes ethical behavior and morality, reinforcing the importance of living a righteous and pious life.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="4" name="An-Nisa" city="Madinah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
        Surah An-Nisa (The Women) is the fourth surah of the Quran, revealed in Medina. It addresses various aspects of social and legal life, with a particular focus on women's rights, family relations, and inheritance laws. This surah emphasizes the importance of justice, protection for the vulnerable, and fairness in Islamic society. Through its teachings, it seeks to establish a balanced society where everyone’s rights are respected.
        </introduction>
        <title>Family Rights and Responsibilities</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Women's Rights</title>
            <description>The surah outlines women's rights concerning marriage, divorce, and inheritance. It aims to establish fair rules for the treatment of women and orphans.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Polygamy</title>
            <description>It addresses the issue of polygamy, stipulating that men can have up to four wives but must treat each of them with fairness and justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Inheritance</title>
            <description>The surah sets clear rules for the distribution of inheritance shares, ensuring fair rights for women and orphans.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Social Justice and Ethics</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Orphan Treatment</title>
            <description>It emphasizes the importance of protecting the rights of orphans and not abusing them.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Justice in Conflicts</title>
            <description>The surah calls for fair conduct in conflicts and disputes, encouraging equitable resolution of conflicts.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Respect for Agreements</title>
            <description>It stresses the importance of respecting agreements and commitments made between individuals.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Rules of Conduct and Morality</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Ethical Behavior</title>
            <description>The surah discusses the ethical and moral behavior expected from believers, including honesty, integrity, and adherence to divine rules.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Behavior in Society</title>
            <description>It provides guidelines for Muslims’ behavior in society, emphasizing the importance of individual and collective responsibility.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Legislation on Crimes</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Sanctions for Crimes</title>
            <description>The surah provides guidelines on sanctions for certain crimes, including those related to family and morality.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Issues of War and Peace</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Conflicts and International Relations</title>
            <description>It addresses issues related to conflicts and international relations, including conduct rules during war and principles of peace.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Reflection on Internal Divisions</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Reconciliation and Unity</title>
            <description>The surah encourages reconciliation between groups and preserving unity within the Muslim community.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Equitable Resource Distribution</title>
            <description>The surah emphasizes equitable resource distribution, particularly regarding inheritance.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Protection of the Vulnerable</title>
            <description>It underscores the need to protect vulnerable groups, such as women and orphans.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Principles of Justice and Ethics</title>
            <description>The surah stresses the importance of justice, ethics, and adherence to social commitments.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="5" name="Al-Ma'idah" city="Madinah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
        Surah Al-Ma'idah (The Table Spread) is the fifth surah of the Quran, revealed in Medina. It addresses various aspects of Islamic law, including dietary rules, religious rites, and relations between Muslims and non-Muslims. The surah emphasizes the necessity of following Allah's commandments, maintaining justice, and adhering to religious obligations. It also deals with social and ethical matters while reminding believers of Allah's blessings and warnings to guide them in their daily lives.
        </introduction>
        <title>Dietary Regulations and Purification</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Dietary Rules</title>
            <description>The surah establishes specific rules regarding permissible and forbidden foods, including the types of meat Muslims can consume and practices related to ritual slaughter.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Purification</title>
            <description>It also addresses matters of purification and cleanliness, and how to prepare for acts of worship.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Legal and Social Regulations</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Laws on Contracts and Transactions</title>
            <description>The surah contains guidelines on commercial transactions, contracts, and financial practices, emphasizing honesty and justice in business dealings.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Penalties and Sanctions</title>
            <description>It specifies penalties for certain crimes and offenses, stressing justice and fairness in the application of the law.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Community and Moral Issues</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Relations with Non-Muslims</title>
            <description>The surah discusses relations between Muslims and non-Muslims, particularly the People of the Book (Jews and Christians), offering advice on peaceful coexistence and mutual respect.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Moral Behavior</title>
            <description>It highlights the importance of morality and ethics in personal and communal interactions.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Reflections on Religious Historiography</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Historical Events</title>
            <description>The surah refers to historical events and incidents involving prophets, drawing lessons on faith and behavior.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Worship and Devotion Issues</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Worship Rituals</title>
            <description>It covers aspects of worship, including religious obligations and practices related to prayer and other forms of devotion.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Dietary Regulations and Purification</title>
            <description>Verses 1-11: Guidelines on permissible (halal) and forbidden (haram) foods, including details on meat and drinks, as well as rules of purification.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Legal and Social Rules</title>
            <description>Verses 12-50: Regulations on commercial transactions, contracts, penalties for certain crimes, and principles of social justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Interfaith Relations and Moral Behavior</title>
            <description>Verses 51-86: Advice on relations with non-Muslims, morality in interactions, and appropriate behavior within the Muslim community.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Historical Reflections and Worship Rituals</title>
            <description>Verses 87-120: Reflections on historical events, religious obligations, and worship practices.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
            <title>Dietary Regulations</title>
            <description>The surah establishes clear rules on permissible and forbidden foods, emphasizing purity and ritual practices.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Social and Legal Laws</title>
            <description>It provides detailed guidelines on commercial transactions, penalties, and principles of social justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
            <title>Interfaith Relations</title>
            <description>The surah encourages peaceful coexistence and respect for diverse religious traditions while affirming Islamic principles.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="6" name="Al-An'am" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
        Surah Al-An'am (The Cattle) is the sixth surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. It primarily deals with faith in Allah, divine Oneness, and signs of His creation. The surah highlights arguments against idolatry and pagan practices while emphasizing the truth of the messages of the prophets. It also addresses principles of Islamic law and Allah's response to the prayers and supplications of the believers. Al-An'am reminds Muslims to follow the path of pure faith and detach from negative influences.
        </introduction>
        <title>Monotheism and Divinity of Allah</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Affirmation of Monotheism</title>
                <description>The surah insists on the Oneness of Allah and the importance of faith in one God. It rejects polytheism and idolatrous practices.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Attributes of Allah</title>
                <description>It describes the attributes of Allah as the Creator, the All-Powerful, and the Master of the universe, highlighting His greatness and sovereignty.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Prophethood and Messengers</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Prophet Stories</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the stories of several prophets, including Noah, Abraham, Moses, and Jesus. These stories serve to illustrate divine messages and moral lessons.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions to the Prophets</title>
                <description>It describes how the prophets faced opposition and criticism from the people they were sent to, and how they responded with patience and perseverance.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Signs of God</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Reflection on Creation</title>
                <description>The surah invites believers to reflect on the signs of God in nature, such as animals, plants, and natural phenomena, as evidence of His existence and divine power.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Miracles and Signs</title>
                <description>It highlights the miracles and signs that God has sent to guide humanity and strengthen the faith of believers.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Belief and Practice Issues</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Critique of Idolatrous Practices</title>
                <description>The surah critiques idolatrous practices and erroneous beliefs of polytheists, while affirming the truth of monotheism.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Guidelines for Believers</title>
                <description>It provides guidelines on how believers should conduct themselves, including how to behave justly and piously in daily life.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Social and Moral Issues</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Justice and Ethics</title>
                <description>The surah addresses principles of justice and ethics, emphasizing the importance of living according to moral values established by God.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Individual Responsibility</title>
                <description>It emphasizes the individual responsibility of each believer to follow divine teachings and live a life in accordance with Islamic principles.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Attributes of Allah</title>
                <description>Verses 1-70: Introduction to Allah's Oneness, His attributes, and the affirmation of monotheism, with reflections on creation and divine signs.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Prophet Stories and Reactions to Messages</title>
                <description>Verses 71-123: Stories of prophets such as Noah, Abraham, Moses, and Jesus, and the challenges they faced. Critique of opponents to prophetic messages.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Guidelines for Believers and Moral Issues</title>
                <description>Verses 124-165: Guidelines on the behavior of believers, critique of idolatrous practices, and moral advice for living a just life.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Affirmation of Monotheism</title>
                <description>The surah reinforces belief in Allah's Oneness and rejects polytheism.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reflection on Divine Signs</title>
                <description>It invites reflection on the signs of God in nature and life events to strengthen faith.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Prophet Stories</title>
                <description>The stories of the prophets illustrate divine messages and moral lessons from their lives and trials.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="7" name="Al-A'raf" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Al-A'raf (The Heights) is the seventh surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. It narrates the stories of several prophets to illustrate the consequences of divine obedience or rejection. The term "Al-A'raf" refers to a high place between Paradise and Hell. The surah highlights the struggle between good and evil, the importance of following the prophets, and Allah's mercy for those who repent. It calls for faith, patience, and vigilance.
        </introduction>
        <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Importance of Revelation</title>
                <description>The surah begins with an affirmation of divine revelation, emphasizing the truth and importance of the Quranic message as a guide for humanity.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Declaration of Monotheism</title>
                <description>It insists on faith in one God, Allah, and rejects polytheism and idolatrous practices.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Prophet Stories and Communities</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Prophet Stories</title>
                <description>The surah narrates the stories of several prophets, including Adam, Noah, Abraham, Moses, and the communities they were sent to. These stories illustrate the divine messages and moral lessons associated with their lives.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions to the Prophets</title>
                <description>It describes how the prophets faced opposition and challenges from their communities, and how they responded with patience and perseverance.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Description of Judgment</title>
                <description>The surah provides a description of the Day of Judgment, including rewards for the pious and punishments for the wicked. It emphasizes the importance of individual responsibility and actions in the afterlife.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Fate of Sinners</title>
                <description>It describes the fate of those who rejected divine messages and engaged in sin.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Moral and Ethical Principles</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Moral Behavior</title>
                <description>The surah addresses moral and ethical principles, focusing on appropriate behaviors and Islamic values.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Individual Responsibility</title>
                <description>It emphasizes individual responsibility to follow divine teachings and lead a just and pious life.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Trials and Tests</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Lesson from Trials</title>
                <description>The surah discusses trials and tests faced by believers, and how these trials are opportunities to strengthen faith and patience.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Example of Satan</title>
                <description>It narrates the story of Satan and his refusal to prostrate before Adam, illustrating the consequences of disobedience to Allah.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Introduction to Revelation and Monotheism</title>
                <description>Verses 1-56: Introduction to divine revelation, the importance of monotheism, and initial stories of the prophets, including Adam and Noah.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Prophet Stories and Community Reactions</title>
                <description>Verses 57-122: Stories of prophets such as Abraham, Moses, and the communities they were sent to. Reactions of the communities to prophetic messages.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Day of Judgment and Consequences of Actions</title>
                <description>Verses 123-206: Description of the Day of Judgment, rewards and punishments, and the fate of sinners.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Moral and Ethical Principles</title>
                <description>Verses 207-208: Guidelines on morality, individual responsibility, and ethical behaviors expected from believers.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>The surah reinforces faith in Allah and the importance of the Quranic message.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Prophet Stories</title>
                <description>The stories of the prophets serve to illustrate divine messages and moral lessons.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>It highlights the Day of Judgment and the importance of actions and individual responsibility.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Trials and Tests</title>
                <description>It addresses trials as opportunities to strengthen faith and patience.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="8" name="Al-Anfal" city="Madinah">
   <section id="1">
        <introduction> 
        Surah Al-Anfal (The Spoils) is the eighth surah of the Quran, revealed in Madinah. It is named after the verses that address the rules concerning the distribution of war booty after the Battle of Badr, a decisive victory for the Muslims. This surah deals with themes such as faith, courage, the unity of the believers, and total dependence on Allah for victory. Al-Anfal emphasizes the importance of discipline and justice in military affairs while reminding the believers that success comes from the will of Allah. It also calls for patience, solidarity among Muslims, and the fulfillment of religious obligations in times of peace as well as in times of war.
        </introduction>
     <title>The Rules of War Booty</title>
         <content>
        <item>
            <title>Distribution of Booty</title>
            <description>The surah provides guidelines on how to distribute the war booty after a battle, defining the shares reserved for the Prophet, the community, and the fighters.</description>
         </item>
         <item>
                <title>Rules of Conduct</title>
                <description>It sets out rules on conduct during wartime, emphasizing justice and ethics even in conflict situations.</description>
        </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>The Consequences of the Believers' Actions</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Behavior of Believers</title>
                <description>The surah addresses the expected behavior of believers during wartime, including the importance of solidarity, loyalty, and faith.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions to Trials</title>
                <description>It discusses the reactions of believers to trials and challenges, emphasizing the importance of patience and perseverance.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>The Importance of Obedience and Trust in Allah</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Obedience to the Prophet</title>
                <description>The surah stresses the importance of following the Prophet Muhammad’s directives and trusting his decisions, especially in matters of war and community management.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Trust in Allah</title>
                <description>It highlights the necessity of placing trust in Allah and relying on Him for success and victory.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>The Reminder of Victories and Failures</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Battle of Badr</title>
                <description>The surah recalls the events of the Battle of Badr, including the decisive victory of the Muslims, and the significance of this victory for the Muslim community.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Lessons from Failures</title>
                <description>It draws lessons from failures and challenges faced, emphasizing the importance of learning and preparation for the future.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Principles of Justice and Morality</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical Principles</title>
                <description>The surah discusses principles of justice and morality, even in wartime, stressing adherence to ethical rules and divine laws.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Responsibility of Leaders</title>
                <description>It underscores the responsibility of Muslim leaders to govern with justice and fairness, respecting divine laws and protecting individual rights.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
    <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Distribution of Booty and Rules of Conduct</title>
                <description>Verses 1-10: Guidelines on the distribution of booty, rules of conduct during war, and expected behaviors of believers.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Behavior of Believers and Reactions to Trials</title>
                <description>Verses 11-24: Discussion on the behavior of believers, patience in the face of trials, and the necessity of following the Prophet’s directives.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Events of the Battle of Badr and Lessons Learned</title>
                <description>Verses 25-40: Reminder of the events of the Battle of Badr, victories and lessons learned, and the importance of trust in Allah.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Principles of Justice and Morality</title>
                <description>Verses 41-75: Principles of justice, responsibility of leaders, and guidelines for ethical conduct in all affairs.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
    <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>War Booty</title>
                <description>The surah provides clear guidelines on the management and distribution of war booty, while establishing rules of conduct.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Obedience and Trust in Allah</title>
                <description>It emphasizes the importance of following the Prophet’s directives and placing trust in Allah for successes and challenges.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Lessons from Events</title>
                <description>It recalls the lessons learned from historical events, such as the Battle of Badr, to reinforce the faith and preparedness of believers.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="9" name="At-Tawbah" city="Madinah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction> 
        Surah At-Tawbah (The Repentance) is the ninth surah of the Quran, revealed in Medina. This surah is unique as it is the only one that does not begin with the phrase "Bismillah" (In the name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful). It addresses topics related to the conduct of Muslims in times of conflict, managing alliances, and the importance of repentance. At-Tawbah highlights the necessity of sincerity in faith, commitment to religious obligations, and repentance for sins. It also contains directives regarding hypocrites and enemies of Islam, while reminding of Allah's mercy for those who repent sincerely and seek reform.
        </introduction>
        <title>Reactions to Disbelievers and Hypocrites</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Relations with Disbelievers</title>
                <description>The surah addresses relations with non-believers, particularly those who have violated treaties or conspired against Muslims. It imposes severe measures against those who betray their commitments or are hostile towards the Muslim community.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Hypocrisy and Disqualification</title>
                <description>It criticizes the hypocrites (munafiqeen) who claim to be Muslims while working against the interests of the Muslim community. The surah calls for vigilance and separation of true believers from hypocrites.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Directives on Alliances and Treaties</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Treaties and Alliances</title>
                <description>The surah deals with rules regarding treaties and alliances with non-Muslims. It specifies the conditions under which these agreements can be annulled and the appropriate actions in case of violation.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>War and Peace</title>
                <description>It addresses the conditions under which war is justified and the principles of conduct during conflict, while encouraging peace and justice.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Importance of Repentance and Forgiveness</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Call to Repentance</title>
                <description>The surah emphasizes the importance of sincere repentance and returning to Allah for those who have sinned or been disloyal. It offers advice on how to repent and seek divine forgiveness.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Forgiveness and Reconciliation</title>
                <description>It encourages reconciliation and forgiveness while specifying the necessary conditions for repentance to be accepted.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Directives on Charity and Almsgiving</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Almsgiving and Charity</title>
                <description>The surah provides directives on the distribution of alms and charity, emphasizing the importance of supporting Islamic causes and taking care of the needy.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Critique of Leaders and Conduct of Believers</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Responsibility of Leaders</title>
                <description>It criticizes leaders who do not adhere to commitments and Islamic principles. It stresses the importance of integrity and justice in managing public affairs.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Behavior of Believers</title>
                <description>The surah provides advice on the appropriate behavior of believers, including their attitude towards faith, other Muslims, and non-believers.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions to Disbelievers and Hypocrites</title>
                <description>Verses 1-37: Critique of disbelievers and hypocrites, rules on relations with them, and conditions for breaking treaties.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Directives on Alliances and Treaties</title>
                <description>Verses 38-72: Directives on alliances, treaties, and appropriate actions during war or conflict.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Importance of Repentance and Forgiveness</title>
                <description>Verses 73-129: Call to sincere repentance, advice on how to repent and seek Allah's forgiveness, and encouragement towards reconciliation.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Directives on Charity and Almsgiving</title>
                <description>Verses 120-129: Directives on charity, almsgiving, and the importance of supporting Islamic causes and the needy.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Relations with Disbelievers</title>
                <description>The surah deals with relations with non-believers, imposing measures against those who betray commitments or conspire against Muslims.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Repentance and Forgiveness</title>
                <description>It emphasizes the importance of sincere repentance and forgiveness, providing advice for returning to Allah.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Directives on Alliances</title>
                <description>It provides rules regarding alliances and treaties, establishing conditions for their annulment in case of violation.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="10" name="Yunus" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
        Surah Yunus is the tenth surah of the Quran, revealed in Mecca. It is named after the prophet Yunus (Jonah), known for his story of repentance and return to Allah after being swallowed by a great fish. This surah addresses themes of divine mercy, the call to faith, and patience in the face of trials. It emphasizes the importance of belief in Allah’s Oneness, the truth of the prophetic message, and the consequences of disbelief. Through the example of Yunus, the surah demonstrates that even the greatest difficulties can be overcome through faith and sincere repentance.
        </introduction>
        <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Affirmation of Monotheism</title>
                <description>The surah begins with a declaration of Allah’s Oneness and the truth of the Quranic revelation. It reaffirms the belief in one all-powerful God.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Importance of Revelation</title>
                <description>It highlights that the Quran is divine guidance for humanity and invites people to reflect on Allah’s signs in nature and their lives.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Story of Prophet Jonah</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Jonah</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the story of Prophet Jonah, including his call to faith, his flight, his stay in the belly of the great fish, and his return to preach to his people.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Lesson of Patience and Repentance</title>
                <description>The story of Jonah is used to illustrate themes of patience, repentance, and divine forgiveness. It shows how sincere repentance can lead to the remission of sins.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Stories of Other Prophets</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Prophets' Stories</title>
                <description>The surah mentions the stories of several other prophets, including Moses and Pharaoh, to illustrate the consequences of disbelief and rebellion against divine messages.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Peoples</title>
                <description>It describes how the peoples of the prophets reacted to their messages and the consequences of their rejection of faith.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Description of Judgment</title>
                <description>The surah provides a description of the Day of Judgment, highlighting the rewards for the righteous and the punishments for the wicked. It emphasizes the importance of actions and faith for eternity.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Rewards and Punishments</title>
                <description>It underscores divine justice by rewarding good deeds and punishing wicked acts.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Guidelines for Believers</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Behavior of Believers</title>
                <description>The surah offers guidance on how believers should behave, including how to respond to challenges, practice patience, and maintain faith.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reflection on Allah’s Signs</title>
                <description>It invites believers to reflect on Allah’s signs in nature and use this reflection to strengthen their faith.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Affirmation of Monotheism and Importance of Revelation</title>
                <description>Verses 1-16: Introduction on Allah’s Oneness, the truth of the Quran, and the importance of reflecting on divine signs.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Prophet Jonah</title>
                <description>Verses 17-48: Story of Jonah, his call, flight, stay in the fish’s belly, and his mission to preach repentance to his people.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of Other Prophets</title>
                <description>Verses 49-109: Stories of Moses, Pharaoh, and other prophets, and lessons from the reactions of peoples to divine messages.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Day of Judgment and Guidelines for Believers</title>
                <description>Verses 110-109: Description of the Day of Judgment, rewards and punishments, and advice for believers on behavior and faith.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>The surah reinforces the belief in a single God and the Quranic revelation as divine guidance.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Jonah</title>
                <description>The story of Jonah illustrates patience, repentance, and divine mercy.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>The surah provides a description of the Day of Judgment and highlights divine justice by rewarding and punishing actions.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="11" name="Hud" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Hud is the eleventh surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. It is named after the Prophet Hud, one of the prophets sent to the `Ād tribe, an ancient civilization known for its power as well as its arrogance and rejection of divine messages. Surah Hud highlights the stories of several prophets, including Nuh (Noah), Salih, Ibrahim (Abraham), Lut (Lot), Shu'ayb, and Hud, to illustrate the consequences of rejecting divine guidance and the importance of faith and obedience to Allah. Through these stories, the surah emphasizes Allah’s mercy for those who believe and repent, while warning of severe consequences for those who persist in disbelief and injustice.
        </introduction>
        <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Affirmation of Monotheism</title>
                <description>The surah begins with a declaration of Allah's uniqueness, the truth of the Quranic revelation, and the necessity of believing in a single God.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Call to Reflection</title>
                <description>It invites people to reflect on the signs of God in nature and to understand the gravity of the divine message.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Hud</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the story of Prophet Hud, who was sent to the `Ād, a people living in the Arabian region. Hud preached the oneness of God and called his people to repent, but they rejected his message and were punished by a devastating storm.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of Other Prophets</title>
                <description>The surah includes the stories of several other prophets, including Noah, Abraham, Salih, and Lot, and the lessons learned from their missions and the reactions of their peoples.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>The Consequences of Rejecting Divine Messages</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Punishment of the Peoples</title>
                <description>The surah describes the punishments inflicted on the peoples who rejected divine messages and prophets, highlighting God's justice and the consequences of sin and disbelief.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Lesson of Repentance</title>
                <description>It teaches that sincere repentance and faith in Allah can lead to forgiveness and divine mercy.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Description of Judgment</title>
                <description>The surah provides a description of the Day of Judgment, emphasizing reward for the righteous and punishment for the wicked. It underscores the importance of actions and faith in view of eternity.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Divine Justice</title>
                <description>It emphasizes God's justice in the retribution of human actions, rewarding the good and punishing the wicked.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Principles of Morality and Ethics</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Behavior of Believers</title>
                <description>The surah offers advice on the moral and ethical behavior expected of believers, emphasizing the necessity of following divine teachings and leading a just life.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Importance of Patience and Perseverance</title>
                <description>It encourages believers to demonstrate patience and perseverance in the face of difficulties and trials.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>Verses 1-10: Introduction to Allah’s oneness, the truth of the Quran, and the call to reflect on divine signs.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Verses 11-83: Stories of Hud, Noah, Abraham, Salih, and Lot, and the lessons learned from the reactions of their peoples to divine messages.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Consequences of Rejection and The Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>Verses 84-95: Description of the punishments inflicted on disbelieving peoples, the lessons of repentance, and the description of the Day of Judgment.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Principles of Morality and Ethics</title>
                <description>Verses 96-123: Moral and ethical guidelines for believers, importance of patience and perseverance.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>The surah reaffirms belief in a single God and the importance of the Quranic message.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>The stories of the prophets illustrate lessons of patience, repentance, and divine justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Consequences of Rejection</title>
                <description>It highlights the consequences of rejecting divine messages and the importance of faith to avoid punishment.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="12" name="Joseph" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Yusuf is the twelfth surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. It narrates in detail the story of the prophet Yusuf (Joseph), known for his beauty, wisdom, and patience in facing trials. This surah is unique in the Quran as it recounts the entire story of Yusuf in a single continuous narrative, highlighting themes such as jealousy, betrayal, temptation, perseverance, and reconciliation. Through Yusuf's story, the surah teaches the power of faith, the value of patience, and the certainty that divine justice always prevails, even after the greatest trials.
        </introduction>
        <title>Youth and Betrayal</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Youth and Vision</title>
                <description>The surah begins with the prophetic vision of Joseph, in which he sees eleven stars, the sun, and the moon prostrating before him. This vision symbolizes his future important role.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Betrayal and Sale</title>
                <description>Joseph is betrayed by his brothers, who, out of jealousy, throw him into a well before selling him as a slave to merchants.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Trials in Egypt</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Trial in Egypt</title>
                <description>Joseph is bought by an Egyptian dignitary and raised in his house. He is later falsely accused by his master's wife and imprisoned.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Dream Interpretation in Prison</title>
                <description>In prison, Joseph interprets the dreams of his fellow inmates, which later leads to his rise when he interprets the dreams of the king of Egypt.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Reconciliation and Forgiveness</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Reconciliation and Forgiveness</title>
                <description>Joseph ultimately reconciles with his brothers, forgives them for their betrayal, and reunites them with their family.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Themes of Patience and Perseverance</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Patience in the Face of Trials</title>
                <description>The surah highlights Joseph’s patience in the face of trials, injustice, and betrayal. His story is an example of resilience and trust in Allah.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Perseverance in Faith</title>
                <description>Joseph remains steadfast in his faith and principles despite the challenges and injustices he faces.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Lessons on Forgiveness and Reconciliation</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Forgiving Offenses</title>
                <description>Joseph’s story illustrates the importance of forgiveness and reconciliation, even towards those who have committed serious wrongs.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Family Reconciliation</title>
                <description>The surah shows how forgiveness can lead to healing and reconciliation within the family.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Trust in Allah and Divine Reward</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Trust in Divine Guidance</title>
                <description>Joseph trusts in divine guidance throughout his trials, and his patience is rewarded with a high position and a successful life.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reward for the Righteous</title>
                <description>The surah emphasizes that justice and faith are ultimately rewarded by Allah.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>The Role of Prophets as Examples</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Behavioral Model</title>
                <description>Joseph's story is presented as a behavioral model for believers, showing how prophets handle trials, betrayal, and reconciliation.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="8">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Youth and Betrayal</title>
                <description>Verses 1-20: Introduction to the story of Joseph, his vision, betrayal by his brothers, and sale as a slave.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Trials in Egypt</title>
                <description>Verses 21-35: Joseph in Egypt, his trials in his master's house, his imprisonment, and his interpretation of dreams in prison.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Dream Interpretation and Rise</title>
                <description>Verses 36-50: Interpretation of the dreams of the king of Egypt, Joseph's rise to a high position, and managing crises in Egypt.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reconciliation and Forgiveness</title>
                <description>Verses 51-101: Reconciliation with his brothers, forgiveness, family reunion, and Joseph’s final instructions to his brothers.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="9">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Patience and Perseverance</title>
                <description>Joseph's story highlights patience and perseverance in the face of trials.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Forgiveness and Reconciliation</title>
                <description>It illustrates the importance of forgiveness and reconciliation, even with those who have betrayed.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Trust in Allah</title>
                <description>The surah shows that trust in Allah and faith are ultimately rewarded.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="13" name="The Thunder" city="Madinah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Ar-Ra'd (The Thunder) is the thirteenth surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. This surah takes its name from the natural phenomenon of thunder, mentioned as a sign of Allah's power and grandeur. It explores profound themes related to faith, divine truth, and revelation. Ar-Ra'd highlights the contrast between those who accept Allah's guidance and those who reject it, while reminding that the signs of His creation are present everywhere in the universe for those who reflect. The surah calls for patience and perseverance in the path of faith.
        </introduction>
        <title>Oneness of God and Signs in Nature</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Oneness of God</title>
                <description>The surah begins with the affirmation of Allah’s oneness and the truth of the Quran as a divine revelation. It emphasizes that the Quran is a guide for humanity and a confirmation of previous revelations.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Sign of God in Nature</title>
                <description>It invites people to reflect on the signs of God in nature, such as thunder, rain, and mountains, to recognize His power and creation.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Reaction of the Disbelievers and Responses to Objections</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
                <description>The surah addresses the reactions of disbelievers to divine signs and prophetic revelations. It highlights their skepticism and rejection of the truth.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Responses to Objections</title>
                <description>It responds to the objections of disbelievers regarding prophecy and revelation, explaining the reasons for the revelation and the mission of the prophets.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Description of Judgment</title>
                <description>The surah provides descriptions of the Day of Judgment, emphasizing the reward for the righteous and the punishment for the unjust. It stresses Allah’s justice and the truthfulness of the warnings given by the prophets.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Rewards and Punishments</title>
                <description>It highlights divine justice by rewarding good deeds and punishing misdeeds.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Prophets and Previous Revelations</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>The surah mentions previous prophets and the revelations given to them, emphasizing that Allah’s message has always been the same throughout history.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Confirmation of Revelations</title>
                <description>It confirms the truth of previous revelations and their consistency with the message of the Quran.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Moral Behavior</title>
                <description>The surah offers advice on moral and ethical behavior, emphasizing the importance of justice, patience, and faith.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Individual Responsibility</title>
                <description>It emphasizes the individual responsibility of each person concerning their actions and beliefs.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Oneness of God and Signs in Nature</title>
                <description>Verses 1-13: Affirmation of Allah’s oneness, divine signs in nature, and the reactions of disbelievers.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers and Responses</title>
                <description>Verses 14-24: Reactions of disbelievers to signs and prophecy, responses to objections, and explanation of the prophetic mission.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>Verses 25-43: Description of the Day of Judgment, rewards and punishments, and divine justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Verses 44-46: Advice on moral behavior, individual responsibility, and the importance of faith.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Oneness and Revelation</title>
                <description>The surah reaffirms Allah’s oneness and the truth of the Quran, inviting reflection on divine signs.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
                <description>It addresses the objections of disbelievers and responds to criticisms of revelation and prophets.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>The surah describes the Day of Judgment and emphasizes divine justice in rewarding human actions.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="14" name="Ibrahim" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Ibrahim is the fourteenth surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. It is named after the prophet Ibrahim (Abraham), a model of faith and devotion. The surah addresses central themes such as gratitude towards Allah, steadfastness in faith, and the consequences of ignoring divine signs. Through the stories of the prophets, particularly that of Ibrahim, it highlights the importance of patience, prayer, and complete reliance on Allah during times of difficulty.
        </introduction>
        <title>Oneness of God and Revelation</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Oneness of God</title>
                <description>The surah begins with the affirmation of Allah’s oneness and the importance of monotheism. It emphasizes that true faith is one that acknowledges the oneness of God and rejects polytheism.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Revelation and Guidance</title>
                <description>It highlights that the Quran is a divine revelation meant to guide people towards truth and justice. The message of revelation is universal and timeless.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Story of Prophet Abraham</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Patience and Devotion</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the story of Prophet Abraham, highlighting his patience, devotion, and unwavering faith in God. It describes how Abraham preached monotheism and opposed idolatry.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Challenges and Trials</title>
                <description>Abraham is presented as a model of faith and perseverance in the face of trials. The surah describes his trials, including his confrontation with King Nimrod and his desire to save his people from idolatry.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Description of Judgment</title>
                <description>The surah provides descriptions of the Day of Judgment, highlighting the recompense for human actions, whether good or bad. It underscores divine justice and the truthfulness of the warnings given by the prophets.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Rewards and Punishments</title>
                <description>It shows how Allah rewards the pious and punishes the unjust, highlighting divine justice in the recompense of human actions.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Reflection on Creation and Nature</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Sign of God in Nature</title>
                <description>The surah invites reflection on the signs of God in nature, such as the creation of the heavens and the earth, to recognize His power and wisdom. These signs are evidence of Allah's existence and greatness.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Moral Behavior</title>
                <description>The surah offers advice on moral and ethical behavior, emphasizing the importance of justice, patience, and faith. It encourages believers to adopt just and virtuous behavior.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Individual Responsibility</title>
                <description>It stresses the individual responsibility of each person concerning their actions and beliefs. People are responsible for their choices and must act according to divine teachings.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Oneness of God and Revelation</title>
                <description>Verses 1-11: Affirmation of Allah’s oneness, the importance of monotheism, and revelation as a guide for humanity.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Prophet Abraham</title>
                <description>Verses 12-41: Account of Abraham’s life, his trials, his opposition to idolatry, and his prayers for his descendants.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>Verses 42-46: Description of the Day of Judgment, recompense for actions, and divine justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reflection on Creation and Nature</title>
                <description>Verses 47-52: Invitation to reflect on the signs of God in nature as evidence of His power and wisdom.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Verses 53-56: Advice on moral behavior, individual responsibility, and the importance of faith.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>Affirmation of the oneness of God and the truth of the Quran as a divine guide.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Abraham</title>
                <description>Patience, devotion, and faith of Abraham in the face of trials.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>Description of judgment, divine recompense for human actions.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reflection on Creation</title>
                <description>Sign of God in nature as evidence of His greatness.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="15" name="Al-Hijr" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Al-Hijr is the fifteenth surah of the Quran, revealed in Mecca. It addresses themes such as divine signs, the stories of the prophets, and the consequences of rejecting revelation. Al-Hijr highlights the story of the people of Thamud and the prophet Salih, as well as other communities that rejected divine warnings. The surah emphasizes Allah's mercy for those who believe and repent, while warning of the consequences for those who persist in disbelief. It also underscores the importance of faith, patience, and obedience to Allah's commands.
        </introduction>

        <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Oneness of God</title>
                <description>The surah asserts the oneness of Allah and the truth of the revelation. It emphasizes that the Quran is a divine guidance sent to guide humanity.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Revelation and Prophecy</title>
                <description>The surah confirms the reality of divine revelation and the prophets sent to convey Allah's message.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Prophet Stories</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Salih and the Thamud</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the story of Prophet Salih and his people, the Thamud. It describes how Salih was sent by Allah to warn the Thamud of their idolatry and sins, and how they were punished for rejecting the divine message.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Abraham and his Wife</title>
                <description>The surah also mentions the story of Abraham (Ibrahim) and the announcement of the birth of his son Isaac (Ishaq) and Jacob (Ya'qub), highlighting Abraham's faith and patience through trials.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Skepticism and Rejection</title>
                <description>The surah addresses the reactions of disbelievers to divine signs and prophetic revelations. It describes their skepticism and rejection of the message, as well as the consequences of their attitude.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Description of Judgment</title>
                <description>The surah provides insights into the Day of Judgment, highlighting the retribution of human actions and divine justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Rewards and Punishments</title>
                <description>It emphasizes that the righteous will be rewarded and the wicked will be punished according to divine justice.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Moral Conduct</title>
                <description>The surah offers advice on moral conduct, highlighting the importance of justice, faith, and patience.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Individual Responsibility</title>
                <description>It emphasizes individual responsibility for one's actions and beliefs.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>Verses 1-15: Affirmation of Allah's oneness, revelation as divine guidance, and the reality of prophets.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Prophet Stories</title>
                <description>Verses 16-39: Story of the Thamud and Prophet Salih, as well as Abraham's story and the announcement of his children's birth.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
                <description>Verses 40-55: Reactions of disbelievers to divine signs and prophetic messages.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>Verses 56-77: Description of the Day of Judgment, retribution of human actions, and divine justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Verses 78-99: Advice on moral conduct, individual responsibility, and the importance of faith.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>Affirmation of God's oneness and the truth of the Quran as divine guidance.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Prophet Stories</title>
                <description>Stories of Prophets Salih and Abraham, and the rejection of divine messages by certain peoples.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
                <description>Description of disbelievers' reactions to divine signs.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>Insights into the Last Judgment and divine justice.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="16" name="An-Nahl" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah An-Nahl (The Bee) is the sixteenth surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. It discusses the signs of Allah’s creation, including those found in nature such as bees, which symbolize wisdom and the diversity of divine blessings. The surah also addresses the principles of faith, moral commandments, and the importance of gratitude towards Allah. It highlights the consequences of rejecting divine truth and encourages believers to persevere in faith, patience, and submission to Allah. An-Nahl also reminds of Allah's mercy and His ability to reward righteous deeds.
        </introduction>
        
        <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Oneness of God</title>
                <description>The surah begins with the affirmation of Allah’s oneness and the importance of monotheism. It emphasizes that only Allah is worthy of worship and that the Quran is a divine revelation sent to guide humanity.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Divine Revelation</title>
                <description>It highlights the reality of revelation and prophets, stressing that the Quran confirms earlier revelations and completes the divine message.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>Signs of God in Nature</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Creation and Nature</title>
                <description>The surah invites reflection on the signs of God in nature, particularly the bees and their organization, as evidence of Allah’s power and wisdom. It describes the benefits of bees, such as honey production and their role in pollination.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Blessings and Benefits</title>
                <description>It mentions various blessings from Allah for humanity, such as food, water, and the products of the earth, emphasizing the gratitude that believers should feel for these blessings.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Ancient Prophets</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the stories of the prophets and messengers sent by Allah to guide their people. It emphasizes the continuity of the divine message through the ages and the resistance of some peoples to the revelations.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Trust and Patience</title>
                <description>It highlights the patience and trust of the prophets in facing difficulties and the resistance of their peoples.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Moral Conduct</title>
                <description>The surah provides guidance on moral and ethical behavior, emphasizing justice, patience, and gratitude towards Allah’s blessings.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Individual Responsibility</title>
                <description>It stresses the responsibility of each person regarding their actions and beliefs, encouraging living according to divine principles.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Skepticism and Rejection</title>
                <description>The surah addresses the reactions of disbelievers to divine signs and prophetic revelations. It describes their skepticism and rejection of the divine message, as well as the consequences of their attitude.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>Verses 1-21: Affirmation of Allah’s oneness, the importance of monotheism, and revelation as divine guidance.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Signs of God in Nature</title>
                <description>Verses 22-30: Description of divine signs in nature, especially bees, and the benefits of creation.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Verses 31-43: Narratives of prophets and messengers, highlighting their patience and dedication.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Verses 44-60: Guidance on moral and ethical behavior, individual responsibility, and gratitude towards Allah’s blessings.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
                <description>Verses 61-128: Reactions of disbelievers to divine signs, revelation, and the warnings of prophets.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Monotheism and Revelation</title>
                <description>Affirmation of the oneness of God and the truth of the Quran as divine guidance.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Signs in Nature</title>
                <description>Reflection on the signs of God in nature, particularly bees, and the benefits of creation.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Narratives of prophets, highlighting their patience and the continuity of the divine message.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Guidance on moral conduct and gratitude towards Allah’s blessings.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
                <description>Description of the disbelievers’ reactions and the consequences of their attitude.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="17" name="Al-Isra" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Al-Isra (The Night Journey) is the seventeenth surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. It begins with the miraculous event of the Night Journey (Isra) of the Prophet Muhammad from Makkah to Jerusalem, followed by the Ascension (Miraj). The surah addresses themes such as divine guidance, moral responsibility, and principles of faith. It also covers the stories of previous prophets, warns against abuses and injustices, and emphasizes the importance of prayer and recognition of Allah's greatness. Al-Isra reminds believers of the importance of remaining on the path of righteousness and submitting to divine commands.
        </introduction>
        
        <title>The Night Journey</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Mi'raj Journey</title>
                <description>The surah begins with the account of the Night Journey (Isra) of the Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) from Makkah to Jerusalem, and his ascent to the heavens (Miraj). This event is presented as a powerful sign of divine greatness and the validation of the prophetic mission.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Importance of the Journey</title>
                <description>The Night Journey is a key event that confirms the truth of the prophetic message and the importance of faith in Allah.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>The Mission of the Prophets</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Role of the Prophets</title>
                <description>The surah addresses the mission of the prophets as guides sent by Allah to lead people to truth and justice. It emphasizes that each prophet was sent with a specific message for his people.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reaction of the Disbelievers</title>
                <description>It deals with the reactions of the disbelievers and skeptics towards the signs and messages of the prophets, and the consequences of their rejection.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>Allah's Blessings</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Rewards and Punishments</title>
                <description>The surah mentions rewards for those who follow the right path and punishments for those who reject divine warnings. It highlights divine justice in the retribution of human actions.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Blessings of Creation</title>
                <description>It invites reflection on the blessings and signs of Allah in creation, emphasizing the necessity of gratitude and recognition.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>The Laws and Rules</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Moral and Social Rules</title>
                <description>The surah contains directives on moral and ethical behavior, including principles of justice, charity, and respect for human rights.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Individual Responsibility</title>
                <description>It emphasizes the individual responsibility of each person regarding their actions and beliefs, and the necessity to act in accordance with divine teachings.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Stories of Ancient Peoples</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>History of the Children of Israel</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the stories of the Children of Israel and their interactions with the prophets, highlighting their behavior in response to revelations and the consequences of their actions.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Night Journey</title>
                <description>Verses 1-9: The account of the Night Journey of the Prophet Muhammad (PBUH) and his ascension to the heavens. The importance of this event as a divine sign.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Mission of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Verses 10-39: Role of the prophets, reaction of the disbelievers, and teachings of the prophetic mission.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Allah's Blessings</title>
                <description>Verses 40-77: Rewards and punishments, blessings in creation, and the importance of gratitude towards Allah.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Laws and Rules</title>
                <description>Verses 78-109: Directives on moral behavior, social rules, and individual responsibility.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of Ancient Peoples</title>
                <description>Verses 110-111: Stories of the Children of Israel and their interactions with the prophets.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Night Journey</title>
                <description>Importance of the Night Journey (Isra) and the Ascension (Miraj) as validation of the prophetic mission.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Mission of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Role of the prophets and reaction of the disbelievers to the revelations.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Allah's Blessings</title>
                <description>Rewards and punishments, and the importance of gratitude towards Allah.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Laws and Rules</title>
                <description>Directives on moral and social behavior, and individual responsibility.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of Ancient Peoples</title>
                <description>Accounts of the Children of Israel and their interactions with the prophets.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="18" name="Al-Kahf" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Al-Kahf (The Cave) is the eighteenth surah of the Quran, revealed in Mecca. It takes its name from the story of the Companions of the Cave, young believers who took refuge in a cave to escape persecution and were miraculously put to sleep for centuries. The surah also addresses the stories of Moses and Khidr, and Dhul-Qarnayn, to illustrate lessons of faith, patience, and justice. Al-Kahf deals with life's trials, the quest for truth, and the consequences of arrogance and misuse of wealth, while emphasizing the importance of divine guidance and perseverance in faith.
        </introduction>

        <title>The Story of the People of the Cave</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The People of the Cave</title>
                <description>The surah begins with the story of young believers who took refuge in a cave to escape religious persecution. They awaken after a long period of sleep as a miracle to demonstrate Allah's power and the truth of resurrection.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Lesson of Faith and Patience</title>
                <description>This story illustrates faith, patience, and Allah's protection for those who seek refuge in Him.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>The Stories of the Prophets</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Story of Moses and Khidr</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the story of Moses and Khidr (Elijah), a mystical sage, and their three significant events. This story highlights the importance of patience and understanding divine actions that are not always immediately clear.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Story of Dhul-Qarnayn</title>
                <description>It also recounts the story of Dhul-Qarnayn, a just king who travels through the world to establish justice and protect people from oppressors. This story emphasizes themes of justice, divine power, and wise use of power.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>The Trials of Life and Wealth</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Story of the Two Gardens</title>
                <description>The surah describes the story of two men, one rich and the other poor, and how wealth can become a source of arrogance and distrust towards Allah. The story highlights the importance of humility and gratitude for divine blessings.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Moral Lessons</title>
                <description>The surah provides moral and behavioral lessons, emphasizing the importance of faith, patience, gratitude, and justice. It also addresses the dangers of arrogance and excessive attachment to material possessions.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Rewards and Punishments</title>
                <description>The surah addresses the Day of Judgment, emphasizing that human actions will be judged with justice. It describes the rewards for believers and the punishments for disbelievers.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Story of the People of the Cave</title>
                <description>Verses 1-26: The story of the young believers who took refuge in the cave, their miraculous sleep, and their awakening.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Verses 27-82: The story of Moses and Khidr, and Dhul-Qarnayn. Lessons on patience, wisdom, and the use of power.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Trials of Life and Wealth</title>
                <description>Verses 83-110: The story of the two gardens and lessons on humility and gratitude.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Verses 1-26 and 27-82: Guidelines on moral behavior, faith, and justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>Verse 110: Rewards and punishments related to human actions.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The People of the Cave</title>
                <description>Illustrate faith and divine protection.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Moses and Khidr, Dhul-Qarnayn, and lessons on wisdom and justice.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Trials of Life</title>
                <description>Importance of humility and gratitude in the face of divine blessings.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Lessons on moral behavior, faith, and arrogance.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Day of Judgment</title>
                <description>Rewards and punishments for human actions.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

<sura index="19" name="Maryam" city="Makkah">
    <section id="1">
        <introduction>
            Surah Maryam (Mary) is the nineteenth surah of the Quran, revealed in Makkah. It is named after Mary, the mother of the prophet Isa (Jesus), and it recounts her story as well as the miraculous birth of Isa. The surah also highlights the narratives of the prophets Zakariya, Yahya (John the Baptist), and Ibrahim (Abraham), illustrating themes of faith, devotion, and divine mercy. Maryam emphasizes the challenges faced by believers, the purity of faith, and the divine reward for those who remain faithful to Allah’s commandments. It is a testament to divine power and the response to sincere prayers.
        </introduction>
        
        <title>The Story of Mary and Jesus</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Birth of Mary</title>
                <description>The surah begins with the story of Mary's birth and her mother’s prayers for a child dedicated to the service of Allah. Mary is described as a pious and devoted woman.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Annunciation of Jesus</title>
                <description>The surah narrates how the angel Gabriel announces to Mary the birth of Jesus, despite her virginity. The miraculous birth of Jesus is a sign of Allah’s power.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="2">
        <title>The Birth of Jesus and His Miracles</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Miracles of Jesus</title>
                <description>The surah describes the miracles of Jesus, including his virgin birth, his miracles in childhood, and his prophetic mission. Jesus is presented as a prophet sent by Allah to guide the Children of Israel.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Defense of Mary and Jesus</title>
                <description>The surah defends Mary against accusations of slander and affirms her purity and virtue. It emphasizes that Jesus is a servant of Allah and not the son of God, in response to false beliefs.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="3">
        <title>The Stories of the Prophets</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Earlier Prophets</title>
                <description>The surah recounts the stories of the prophets Zakariya, John the Baptist (Yahya), Abraham, and Moses. These narratives illustrate their devotion, trials, and divine mission.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Patience and Devotion</title>
                <description>The stories of the prophets demonstrate their patience, faith in Allah, and dedication to their mission, despite difficulties and opposition.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="4">
        <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Moral Conduct</title>
                <description>The surah provides guidance on moral and ethical conduct, emphasizing faith, patience, and submission to divine will.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Individual Responsibility</title>
                <description>It emphasizes the individual responsibility of each person regarding their actions and beliefs.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="5">
        <title>Reactions and Warnings</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions of the Disbelievers</title>
                <description>The surah addresses the reactions of disbelievers to divine signs and prophetic revelations. It warns against rejecting Allah’s signs and the consequences of disbelief.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="6">
        <title>Detailed Content</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>The Story of Mary and Jesus</title>
                <description>Verses 1-40: The birth of Mary, the annunciation of Jesus, and the defense of Mary and Jesus against accusations.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Birth of Jesus and His Miracles</title>
                <description>Verses 41-50: Miracles of Jesus, his prophetic mission, and aspects of his life.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>The Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Verses 51-98: Narratives of the prophets Zakariya, John the Baptist, Abraham, and Moses, and their lessons.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Verses 1-98: Guidance on moral and ethical conduct, individual responsibility.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions and Warnings</title>
                <description>Verses 99-100: Reactions of the disbelievers and warnings regarding the rejection of divine signs.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
    <section id="7">
        <title>Key Points</title>
        <content>
            <item>
                <title>Story of Mary and Jesus</title>
                <description>Miraculous birth of Jesus, purity of Mary, and defense against false accusations.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Miracles of Jesus</title>
                <description>Description of Jesus’s miracles and prophetic mission.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Stories of the Prophets</title>
                <description>Patience and devotion of the prophets Zakariya, John the Baptist, Abraham, and Moses.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Ethical and Moral Principles</title>
                <description>Importance of faith, patience, and submission to divine will.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Reactions and Warnings</title>
                <description>Reactions of disbelievers and warnings about rejecting Allah’s signs.</description>
            </item>
        </content>
    </section>
</sura>

</quran>